Cohoes, NY (352) 428-8054 dcalabrese22@gmail.com

Daniel Calabrese

dcalabrese22.github.io github.com/dcalabrese22 linkedin.com/in/dcalabrese22 medium.com/@dcalabrese22

Android app developer working on a large project as the lead engineer who excels at analyzing diverse problems, finding and implementing solutions, and documenting results. Experienced remote worker with proven excellence working independently and collaborating with teams as necessary.

Technical Skills

Languages: Kotlin, Java, Javascript, PHP, C++, Python, HTML5, CSS3, SQL/NoSQL, XML Frameworks/Libraries: Android, Swing, JavaFx, Firebase, Retrofit/OkHttp3, Glide, Selenium

Other: Git/GitHub, Android Studio, Linux OS, Mac OS

Personal Projects

Chatter Android App - Chatter on Google Play

November 2017

- Messaging app that utilizes authentication, database, functions, and storage of Google's mobile platform, Firebase.
- Utilized Firebase UI, RecyclerView, Intents, Fragments, and Widget.
- Deployed to the Google Play App Store.

Popular Movies Android App - dcalabrese22.github.io/Discover-Movies/

May 2017

- Mobile app that allows users to browse movies, tag favorites, read reviews, and watch movie trailers.
- Retrieved movie data from online REST API in JSON format and stores data in local SQLite database.

Work Experience

Zerion Software, Inc. - Lead Android Developer

Herndon, VA-remote | 2018-Present

- Android developer responsible for maintaining and adding new features to the <u>iForm</u> app.
- Internal advocate for test driven development, thoughtful architecture, and adhering to SOLID principles.
- Improved app sync performance by reducing sync times approximately 75% by utilizing multithreading with Kotlin coroutines.
- Re-built an annotation tool from scratch that allows for loading or taking a picture and annotating atop of the image by
 drawing with touch, text, shapes, icons, and additional images.. Each annotation can be moved, resized, rotated, and
 deleted. The tool also has undo/redo functionality and final drawing is auto-cropped to remove whitespace from all sides
 and can be saved to external storage.
- Developed internal SDK in Kotlin for interacting with iForm's API that makes use of coroutines and asynchronous flow with a unit/integration test suite of approximately 400 tests.
- Development and maintenance of automated UI testing frameworks for both mobile (using Espresso) and web apps (using Selenium) that automatically run after code merge in order to increase integrity and identify bugs before public release.
- Development of a customer-requested background location tracker feature as an SDK in Kotlin that tracks a user's location at a dynamic interval and sends the location information to a dynamic endpoint with unit, integration, and UI tests.
- Created tool for translating strings using Google Translate.
- Performed map integrations of both Mapbox and Google Maps.

Albany Molecular Research - Service Engineer/Research Scientist

Rensselaer, NY | 2012-2018

- Maintain and administer 2 computer networks and 13 computing environments including computer hardware, systems software, applications software, and all configurations.
- Responsible for the calibration and maintenance of 40 laboratory instruments, which saved approximately \$200,000 yearly and reduced instrument downtime by 50%.

Education

Udacity - Android Developer Nanodegree Hudson Valley CC - Coursework in Computer Information Systems University of South Florida - Biomedical Sciences, B.S. March 2017-December 2017 January 2015-May 2017 December 2008